<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="/dftevn-website/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/dftevn-website/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-03-02T16:34:44+00:00</updated><id>/dftevn-website/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Dftevn</title><subtitle>An engaging 1-3 sentence description of your lab.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Postdoctoral Research Position Announcement</title><link href="/dftevn-website/2024/02/20/posdoc-announcement-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Postdoctoral Research Position Announcement" /><published>2024-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-03-02T16:31:23+00:00</updated><id>/dftevn-website/2024/02/20/posdoc-announcement-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="/dftevn-website/2024/02/20/posdoc-announcement-1.html"><![CDATA[<table>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td>Title:</td>
      <td>Postdoctoral Research Fellow in Atomistic Modelling in Material Science</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Institution:</td>
      <td>Computational Materials Science Laboratory, Yerevan State University</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Location:</td>
      <td><i class="icon fa-solid fa-location-dot"></i> Yerevan, Republic of Armenia</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Application Deadline:</td>
      <td><i class="icon fa-regular fa-calendar"></i> 30 April 2024</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Starting Date:</td>
      <td><i class="icon fa-regular fa-calendar"></i> October 2024</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>Duration::</td>
      <td>2 years</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<h2 id="description">Description:</h2>
<p>CMS Lab invites applications for a Postdoctoral Research Fellow position in Atomistic
Modelling in Materials Science. The successful candidate will join a dynamic and collaborative
research team and work on two projects. The first project is in the framework of
<strong>“Computational materials design and discovery for energy storage applications”</strong> grant by
“Higher Education and Science Committee” of Armenia. This research aims to computationally
find new solid-state electrolytes for Li-ion batteries and new materials for other ion and organic
electrode batteries, plus developing methods to expedite DFT calculations for crystal structure
prediction. By using computational tools and machine learning, we aim to predict, design, and
calculate important features of novel battery materials more efficiently. The research initially
focuses on Li-ion and Na-ion battery materials and later, on K-ion, Mg-ion, and organic
electrode materials.
The second project will be in the framework of <strong>“Second Call of PostDoc-Armenia 2024”</strong> grant,
for which the applicant should propose individual research.</p>

<h2 id="responsibilities">Responsibilities:</h2>

<ol>
  <li>Conduct DFT calculations via VASP.</li>
  <li>Calculate stability Phase diagrams.</li>
  <li>Calculate important features for battery materials: ion conduction, stability window.</li>
  <li>Conduct independent research within the scope of the PostDoc project.</li>
  <li>Collaborate with team members to achieve project milestones.</li>
  <li>Participate in the educational process by collaborating with master's and Ph.D. students, dedicating no more than 20% of your time.</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="qualifications">Qualifications:</h2>

<ol>
  <li>Ph.D. in Materials Science or a related disciplines (Physics, chemistry).</li>
  <li>4 publications in International Scientific Database (Scopus or WOS).</li>
  <li>To be born after January 1, 1984.</li>
  <li>Ph.D received after January 1, 2010.</li>
  <li>Excellent background for solid state physics, DFT and computational physics.</li>
  <li>Experience with computational tools, machine learning, and DFT calculations.</li>
  <li>Ability to work independently and collaboratively within a team.</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="benefits">Benefits:</h2>
<ol>
  <li>The salary starts at around $2200 but has the potential for an increase through
participation in other grants.</li>
  <li>Health insurance.</li>
  <li>Opportunities to participate conferences.</li>
  <li>Access to state-of-the-art facilities and resources in Armenia.</li>
  <li>Opportunities for professional development and networking.</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="application-process">Application Process:</h2>
<ol>
  <li>Interested candidates should submit Curriculum vitae (CV) including a list of
publications to Hayk Zakaryan’s email: <a href="mailto:hayk.zakaryan@ysu.am?subject=PostDoc-Armenia 2024" target="_blank">hayk.zakaryan@ysu.am</a></li>
  <li>After submission first stage will be online interview with PI of CMS Lab.</li>
  <li>Results of the first stage will be announced before 5 May 2024.</li>
  <li>In the second stage, selected applicant will apply to “Second Call of PostDoc-Armenia
2024” grant. Details of the grant are in the following link: <a href="http://hesc.am/files/POSTDOC-2-ENG.pdf" target="_blank">details</a></li>
  <li>The grant results will be announced in September 2024.</li>
</ol>

<h3 id="for-any-inquiries-and-questions-please-write-to-haykzakaryanysuam">For any inquiries and questions please write to <a href="mailto:hayk.zakaryan@ysu.am?subject=PostDoc-Armenia 2024" target="_blank">hayk.zakaryan@ysu.am</a></h3>]]></content><author><name>hayk-zakaryan</name></author><category term="job" /><category term="postdoc" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Title: Postdoctoral Research Fellow in Atomistic Modelling in Material Science Institution: Computational Materials Science Laboratory, Yerevan State University Location: Yerevan, Republic of Armenia Application Deadline: 30 April 2024 Starting Date: October 2024 Duration:: 2 years]]></summary></entry></feed>